<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Yecoder</title>
    <link>https://yecoder.com/categories/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Yecoder</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 13:48:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yecoder.com/categories/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configure Logstash, Elasticsearch, and Kibana with Docker</title>
      <link>https://yecoder.com/posts/configure-logstash-elasticsearch-and-kibana-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 13:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yecoder.com/posts/configure-logstash-elasticsearch-and-kibana-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>It was a long time ago I wanted to write this post and show you how to set up a docker-compose with all you need to have a separate logging system.
Logging is a meaningful way to monitor your application’s behavior. When it comes to production and having multiple servers running one application in different instances, You might want to have a unified logging system to check them all in one place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DBGate - OpenSource and Modern DB Client</title>
      <link>https://yecoder.com/posts/dbgate-opensource-and-modern-db-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yecoder.com/posts/dbgate-opensource-and-modern-db-client/</guid>
      <description>DBGate is an open-source database client which has a modern UI.
I am still checking it but one of the coolest features that I saw was the web application!
You can install the web application on the server and then you have access to the database with an amazing client!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to monitor Laravel application servers</title>
      <link>https://yecoder.com/posts/how-to-monitor-laravel-application-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 12:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yecoder.com/posts/how-to-monitor-laravel-application-servers/</guid>
      <description>Laravel Monitoring is a package by myself so you can monitor your Laravel application’s server resources like CPU, Disk, and Memory
This package provides a beautiful dashboard with a fancy chart showing the server’s resource usage from one hour to a day.
Multi-Server support The amazing part of this package which is my favorite part also, Is you can see monitor all of your servers in one place!
For example, consider that you have several servers running the same source code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
